// creating an array and passing the number, questions, options, and answers
// to script.js and then onto html files and then styled by css file.
let questions = [
    {
    numb: 1,
    question: "When does St Patricks day happen?",
    answer: "17th March",
    options: [
      "17th February",
      "17th March",
      "17th April",
      "17th May"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 2,
    question: "What is the symbol for St Patricks day?",
    answer: "Clover Leaf",
    options: [
      "Heart",
      "Rose",
      "Angel",
      "Clover Leaf"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 3,
    question: "Why do peope wear green clothes on St Patricks day?",
    answer: "To avoid being pinched",
    options: [
      "For luck",
      "For camouflage",
      "To avoid being pinched",
      "Because they're Irish"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 4,
    question: "What was St Patricks name when he was born?",
    answer: "Maewyn Succat",
    options: [
      "Maewyn Succat",
      "Treret Beckette",
      "Alden Batilde",
      "Joseph Murphy"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 5,
    question: "What creature did St Patrick allegedly banish from Ireland?",
    answer: "Snake",
    options: [
      "Bat",
      "Snake",
      "Scorpion",
      "Spider"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 6,
    question: "Which city in the US hosted the first St Patricks day parade?",
    answer: "New York",
    options: [
      "Chicago",
      "San Francisco",
      "Boston",
      "New York"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 7,
    question: "Which dish is often eaten in the US on St Patricks day?",
    answer: "Cabbage and Corned Beef",
    options: [
      "Sauerkraut and Sausage",
      "Ring cake",
      "Cabbage and Corned Beef",
      "Soda Bread"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 8,
    question: "According to old Irish stories, what did the walking stick of St Patrick turn into?",
    answer: "A tree",
    options: [
      "A tree",
      "A sword",
      "A broom",
      "A cross"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 9,
    question: "According to a popular belief what do leprachauns bury at the end of a rainbow?",
    answer: "A pot of gold",
    options: [
      "A shamrock",
      "A pair of shoes",
      "A pot of gold",
      "A bag of sweets"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 10,
    question: "When did green become the symbolic colour of St Patrick?",
    answer: "In the Irish Rebellion in the 18th century",
    options: [
      "In the Irish Rebellion in the 18th century",
      "After the first world war",
      "After the second world war",
      "During the reign of Queen Elizabeth the First"
    ]
  },
];


